A Guide to the Russell Sage Foundation records, Office of the President, Eric Wanner papers, Record Group 1 FA764
Rockefeller Archive Center
Russell Sage Foundation records, Office of the President, Eric Wanner papers, Record Group 1
1989-2010
1962-2010
Rockefeller Archive Center
Russell Sage Foundation
Wanner, Eric
FA764
5.1 Cubic Feet 6 letter document storage boxes, 2 record storage boxes, and 1 Half letter document storage box
8 letter document storage boxes and 1 Half letter document storage box
Biographical / Historical
Eric Wanner was president of the Russell Sage Foundation from 1986 - 2012. The Russell Sage Foundation (RSF) is a foundation devoted to research in social sciences. Eric Wanner developed the Foundation's long-standing research programs on behavioral economics, poverty and inequality in the United States, the economic and social impacts of U.S. immigration.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Arrangement
Material retained orginal order and is organized by working papers number.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to the RAC by Russell Sage Foundation and ingested by the RAC as Accession 2013:077.
Scope and Contents
Contains working papers from the office of Eric Wanner from his time as President of the Russell Sage Foundation.
- Working papers, 1962-2010; 1; 5.1 Cubic Feet 6 letter boxes, 1 half-letter box, 2 record storage boxes
  Sociology; Political science; Anthropology; United States -- Politics and government; Economics -- Research
  - 1 - Anomalies in Intertemporal Choice: Evidence and an Interpretation, 1989 January; Loewenstein, George (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Economics
  - 2 - The Origin of Predictable Dynamic Behavior, 1989 January; Heiner, Ronald (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Heiner, Ronald
  - 3 - The City as a Landscape of Power: London and New York as Global Financial Capitals, 1989 October; Zukin, Sharon (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Sociology
  - 4 - The Dangers of the Underclass; Its Harmfulness as a Planning Concept, 1990 January; Gans, Herbert J. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 5 - The Income Side of Housing Affordability: Shifts in Household Income and Income Support Programs during the 1970s and 1980s, 1990 February; Burt, Martha R. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 6 - Public Private Relations in the Shaping of Social Welfare in America: An Overview, 1990 February; Katz, Michael B. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    History
  - 7 - Surviving Poverty in Early Twentieth Century New York City, 1990 April; Katz, Michael B. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 8 - Testing the Opportunity Cost Hypothesis of Adolescent Premarital Childbearing, 1990 April; Lundberg, Shelly; Plotnick, Robert D. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 9 - The Effect of Distributional Constraints and Interstate Tax Competition on State Decisions to Tax: An Econometric Model, 1990 April; Chernick, Howard (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 10 - Structural Determinants of the Demand for Lotteries, 1990 April; Shapira, Zur; Venezia, Itzhak (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Psychology
  - 11 - Consuming Concerns or From the End of History to the Rise of the New Europe, 1990 October (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: Swedberg, Richard
  - 12 - Inventing Times Square: Commerce and Culture at the Crossroads of the World, 1880-1939, 1990 October; Taylor, William Robert (1922-2014) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 13 - An Almost Random Career, 1990 December; Perrow, Charles (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 14 - Demographic Methods, 1990 December; Bennett, Neil G. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 15 - The Decline of Client Politics: Understanding Reform in the Tax and Regulatory Arenas, 1991 January; Mucciaroni, Gary (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Political science
  - 16 - The Structural Embeddedness of Business Decisions, 1991 February; Romo, Frank; Schwartz, Michael (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 17 - The Blue-Collar Working Class: Structural Discontinuity, 1991 February; Romo, Frank; Halle, David (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 18 - A Critique of the Garbage Can Model of Policy-Making, 1991 February; Mucciaroni, Gary (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 19 - Accidents in High Risk Systems, 1991 April; Perrow, Charles (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 20 - Free Traders and Free Immigrationists: Strangers or Friends?, 1991 April; Bhagwati, Jagdish (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: Bhagwati, Jagdish
  - 21 - In Search of Respect: The New Service Economy and the Crack Alternative in Spanish Harlem, 1991 May; Bourgois, Philippe (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Anthropology
  - 22 - Shooting Gallery Notes, 1991 May; Bourgois, Philippe (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 23 - On the Labor Market Effects of Immigration and Trade, 1991 May; Freeman, Richard B.; Borjas, George J.; Katz, Lawrence F. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 24 - The Relationship Between Economic Theory and Economic Sociology in the Work of Joseph Schumpeter, 1991 June; Swedberg, Richard (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 25 - Feminism and Democratic Community, 1992 January; Mansbridge, Jane J. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 26 - On The Determinants of Children's Wellbeing and Economic Success: A Research Perspective, 1992 January; Haveman, Robert; Wolfe, Barbara Schull (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 27 - Divergent Destinies: Immigration, Poverty, and Entrepreneurship in the United States, 1992 September; Portes, Alejandro (1944); Zhou, Min (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 28 - Can Cognitive Consistency Cure Collective Diemmas? Self-interest versus Duty to Pay Taxes, 1992 October; Pinney, Neil; Scholz, John Karl (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 29 - Labor Force Recomposition and Industrial Restructuring in Electronics: Implications for Free Trade, 1992 October; Kelly, M. Patricia Fernandez (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 30 - Socioeconomic Status and Depression: The Role of Occupations Involving Direction, Control, and Planning, 1992 October; Link, Bruce G.; Lennon, Mary Clare; Dohrenwend, Bruce P. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 31 - The Street-Level Epistemology of Trust, 1992 December; Hardin, Russell (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Government and Public Policy
  - 32 - Enterprise and Labor Markets. The Border and the Metropolitan Areas, 1992 December; Roberts, Bryan (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 33 - Relative Fairness and the Division of Housework: The Importance of Options, 1993 January; Lennon, Mary Clare; Rosenfield, Sarah (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 34 - The New Second Generation: Segmented Assimilation and its Variants among Post-1965 Immigrant Youth, 1993 February; Portes, Alejandro (1944); Zhou, Min (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 35 - Infant Health and the Labor Supply of Mothers, 1993 February; Blau, David M.; Guilkey, David K.; Popkin, Barry M. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 36 - Recasting Women in the Global Economy: Internationalization and Changing Definitions of Gender, 1993 March; Kelly, M. Patricia Fernandez; Sassen, Saskia (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 37 - Political Economy and Gender in Latin America: The Emerging Dilemmas, 1993 April; Kelly, M. Patricia Fernandez (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 38 - Rethinking Citizenship on the Global Village: Reflections on Immigrants and the Underclass, 1993 May; Kelly, M. Patricia Fernandez (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 39 - Norms of Exclusion and Difference, 1993 May; Hardin, Russell (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 40 - Towanda's Triumph: Unfolding the Meanings of Adolescent Pregnancy in the Baltimore Ghetto, 1993 June; Kelly, M. Patricia Fernandez (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 41 - Voices from below: the value of ethnographic research for informing public policy, 1993 June; Jarrett, Robin L. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 42 - Women, Work, and Well-Being: The importance of work conditions, 1993 July; Lennon, Mary Clare (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 43 - Informal Economy and Family Strategies. A Comparative Review, 1993 July; Roberts, Bryan (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 44 - Parental Management Strategies in Low-Income African-American Neighborhoods: Two Styles, 1993 July; Jerrett, Robin L. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 45 - The Return of the Repressed Urban Violence, "Race", and Dualization in Three Advanced Societies, 1993 November; Wacquant, Loic (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 46 - Why Men Desire Muscles?, 1993 November; Wacquant, Loic (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 47 - The Emergence of the Labor Market and Earnings Distribution. The Case of the Czech Republic, 1994 March; Vecernik, Jiri (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 48 - Moral Hazard and Independent Income In a Modern Intertemporal-Equilibrium Model of Involuntary Unemployment and Mandatory Retirement, 1994 March; Phelps, Edmund S. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 49 - Inside the Zone. The Social Art of the Hustler in the Contemporary Ghetto, 1994 April; Wacquant, Loic (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 50 - Gender and Academic Specialties: Trends Among College and Graduate Degree Recipients During the 1980s, 1994 April; Jacobs, Jerry A. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 51 - The Pugilistic Point of View. How Boxers Think and Feel About Their Trade, 1994 April; Wacquant, Loic (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 52 - The Duration of Employment in Part-Time Jobs, 1994 May; Jacobs, Jerry A.; Qian, Zhen Chao (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 53 - A Primer on American Poverty: 1949-1992, 1994 May; Rainwater, Lee (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 54 - The Institutional and Individual Scramble for Resources: Transitional Housing and Homeless Families, 1994 May; Gerstel, Naomi; Schwartz, Michael; Bogard, Cynthia; McConnell, J. Jeff (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 55 - A Program of Low-Wage-Employment Tax Credits: To Pull up the Employment and Wage Rates of the Disadvantated, 1994 May; Phelps, Edmund S. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 56 - A Cross-National Analysis of the Wages of Part-Time Workers: Evidence from the United States, the United Kingdom, Canada, and Australia, 1994 June; Gornick, Janet C.; Jacobs, Jerry A. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 57 - Puerto Ricans in Historical and Social Science Research, 1994 July; Rodriguez, Clara (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 58 - On the Damaging Side Effects of the Welfare System: How, Why and What to Do, 1994 July; Phelps, Edmund S. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 59 - Market Transition and the Commodification of Housing in Urban China, 1994 September; Zhou, Min (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 60 - The Emergence of A Market Society: Changing Mechanisms of Stratification in China, 1994 September; Nee, Victor (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 61 - Job Transitions in an Immigrant Metropolis: Ethnic Boundaries and Mixed Economy, 1994 September; Nee, Victor; Sanders, Jimy M.; Sernau, Scott (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 62 - Basic Instincts? Sources of Firm Preference for National Health Reform, 1994 October; Martin, Cathie Jo (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 63 - Mandating Social Change: The Struggle Within Corporate America Over National Health Reform, 1994 October; Martin, Cathie Jo (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 64 - Institutions, Social Ties, and Commitment in China's Corporatist Transformation, 1994 October; Nee, Victor; Su, Sijin (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 65 - Ideology and Social Practice in the Jamaican Dispora, 1994 November; Foner, Nancy (1945) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 66 - On Money Illusion, 1994 November; Shafir, Eldar; Diamond, Peter; Tversky, Amos (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 67 - Chinatown Revisited: Community-Based Organizations, Immigrant Families, and the Younger Generation, 1994 November; Zhou, Min (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 68 - Family Capital, Human Capital, and Self Employment Among Immigrants, 1994 November; Sanders, Jimy M.; Nee, Victor (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 69 - The Employer Consortium: Improving Job Mobility Among Low-wage Workers in the Inner City, 1995 March; Newman, Katherine (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 70 - Problems in the Evalutaion of Community-Wide Initiatives, 1995 April; Hollister, Robinson G. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 71 - Ethinic Ties in the Immigrant Labor Market: Linking Ethnographic and Event History Analyses, 1995 May; Nee, Victor; Sanders, Jimy M.; Sernau, Scott (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 72 - Embeddedness and Beyond: Institutions, Exchange and Social Structure, 1995 June; Nee, Victor; Ingram, Paul (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 73 - The Dysfunctions of Transnationalism, 1995 July; Mahler, Sarah (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 74 - Perceptions of Racial Group Competition: Extending Blumer's Theory of Group Position to a Multiracial Context, 1995 September; Bobo, Lawrence (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 75 - Surveying Racial Discrimination: Analyses from a Multiethnic Labor Market, 1995 September; Bobo, Lawrence (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 76 - Finding Work In The Inner City: How Hard Is It Now? How Hard Will It Be For AFDC Recipients?, 1995 October; Newman, Katherine; Lennon, Chauncy (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 77 - Employer Screening Methods and Racial Exclusion: Evidence from New In-Depth Interviews with Employers, 1995 October; Kirschenman, Joleen; Moss, Philip; Tilly, Chris (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 78 - Prismatic Metropolis: Race and Residential Segregation in the City of Angels, 1995 October; Bobo, Lawrence; Zubrinsky, Camille (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 79 - Computing and Social Change: Employment and Efficiency, 1995 October; Rule, James B. (1943); Gimlin, Debra (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 80 - "Soft" Skills and Race: An investigation of black men's employment problems, 1995 October; Moss, Philip; Tilly, Chris (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 81 - Raised Hurdles for Black Men: Evidence from Interview with Employers, 1995 November; Moss, Philip; Tilly, Chris (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 82 - Immigration, Inequality, and Policy Alternatives, 1995 November; DeFreitas, Gregory (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 83 - Understanding the Behavior of Actors in Labor Markets, 1995 November; Tilly, Charles; Tilly, Chris (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 84 - Employer Skill Needs and Labor Market Outcomes Across Groups, 1995 December; Holzer, Harry J. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 85 - Spatial Factors and the Employment of Blacks at the Firm Level, 1995 December; Holzer, Harry J.; Ihlanfeldt, Keith R. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 86 - Employer Hiring Decisions and Antidiscrimination Policy, 1995 December; Holzer, Harry J. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 87 - The Color Line, The Dilemma The Dream: Racial Attitudes and Relations in the Twentieth Century, 1995 December; Bobo, Lawrence (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 88 - Making Labor Law Work for Part-Time and Contingent Workers, 1996 January; DuRivage, Virginia; Carre, Francoise J.; Tilly, Chris (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 89 - Space as a Signal, Space as Barrier: How Employers Map and Use Space in Four Metropolitan Labor Markets, 1996 February; Kirschenman, Joleen; Moss, Philip; Tilly, Chris (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 90 - Considerations of Race, Universalism, and Deconcentration, 1996 February; Thompson, J. Phillip (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 91 - The End of Liberalism in New York: Homeless Policy in the Dinkins Era, 1996 February; Thompson, J. Phillip (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 92 - Workfare's Impact on the New York City Labor Market: Lower Wages and Worker Displcement, 1996 March; Tilly, Chris (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 93 - Growing Demand for "Soft" Skills in Four Industries: Evidence from In-Depth Employer Interviews, 1996 March; Moss, Philip; Tilly, Chris (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 94 - Getting to the Glass Ceiling: Obstacles to Women in the Workforce, 1996 April; Albelda, Randy; Tilly, Chris (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 95 - The Effect of Measured School Inputs on Academic Achievement: Evidence from the 1920s, 1930s and 1940s Brith Cohorts, 1996 May; Loeb, Susanna; Bound, John (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 96 - Separating Fiction from Reality: A Case Against Dismantling and Devolving The Federal Safety Net, 1996 May; Caraley, Demetrios (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 97 - What Teen Mothers Know, 1996 May (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Policy; Government; American politics
  - 98 - Laissez Faire Racism: The Crystalization of a `Kinder, Gentler' Anti-Black Ideology, 1996 June; Bobo, Lawrence; Kluegel, James R.; Smith, Ryan A. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 99 - The Erosion of the Relative Earnings of Young Black American Women During the 1980s, 1996 June; Bound, John; Dresser, Laura (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 100 - Trade and Networks: An Application to Minority Retail Entrepreneurship, 1996 June; Rauch, James E. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 101 - Teenage Childbearing and Personal Responsibility: An Alternative View, 1996 June; Geronimus, Arline T. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Government; Policy; Politics, Practical
  - 102 - Demand Shifts, Population Adjustments, and Labor Market Outcomes during the 1980s, 1996 July; Bound, John; Holzer, Harry J. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 103 - The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly: Good and Bad Jobs in the United States at the Millennium, 1996 July; Tilly, Chris (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 104 - Inequality by Design: Myths, Data, and Politics, 1996 October; Hout, Michael (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 105 - Rationality and Interpretation: The Politics of Transition, 1996 December; Bates, Robert H.; Weingast, Barry R. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 106 - Educational Vouchers: Effectiveness, Choice, and Costs, 1997 January; Levin, Henry M. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 107 - Games with Procedurally Rational Players, 1997 February; Osborne, Martin J.; Rubinstein, Ariel (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 108 - The Way We Were (And Are): Changes in Public Finance and Its Textbook, 1997 March; Rosen, Harvey S. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 109 - Immigrant Groups and Suburbs: A Test of Spatial Assimilation Theory, 1997 March; Alba, Richard A.; Logan, John R.; Marzun, Gilbert; Stults, Brian; Zhang, Wenquan (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 110 - The Rhetorics of Racism and Anti-Racism in France and the United States, 1997 April; Lamont, Michele (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 111 - Inequality at the Margins: The Effects of Welfare, the Minimum Wage, and Tax Credits on Low-Wage Labor Markets, 1997 April; Hout, Michael (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 112 - White Ethnics in the New York Economy, 1920-1960, 1997 April; Logan, John R. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 113 - The Ethnic Neighborhood, 1920-1970, 1997 May; Logan, John R. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 114 - Debates and Decisions: On A Rationale of Argumentation Rules, 1997 June; Glazer, Jacob; Rubinstein, Ariel (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 115 - Ritual Healing and the Politics of Identity in Contemporary Navajo Society, 1997 July; Csordas, Thomas J. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 116 - Computerized Cadavera: Shades of Being and Representation in Virtual Reality, 1997 July; Csordas, Thomas J. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 117 - Assimilation and Its Discontents: Between Rhetoric and Reality, 1997 September; Rumbaut, Ruben G. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 118 - The Origins of technology-skill complementary, 1997 October; Goldin, Claudia; Katz, Lawrence F. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 119 - Computer technology, human labor, and long-run economic growth, 1997 October; Elliott, Stuart W. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 120 - Self-employment, family background, and race, 1997 October; Hout, Michael; Rosen, Harvey S. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 121 - Unskilled immigration and changes in the wage distributions of Black, Mexican American, and Non-Hispanic White male dropouts, 1997 October; Reimers, Cordelia W. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 122 - Horatio Alger meets the mobility tables, 1997 October; Holtz-Eakin, Douglas; Rosen, Harvey S.; Weathers, Robert (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 123 - Sex, kids, and commitment to the workplace: employers, employees and the mommy track, 1997 November; Preston, Anne E. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 124 - Distrust and the development of urban regulations, 1997 December; Troy, Patrick (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 125 - Showing what you are by showing who you are, 1997 December; Bacharch, Michael (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 126 - Trust in signs, 1997 December; Bacharch, Michael; Gambetta, Diego (1952) (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 127 - Human capital and social capital: the rise of secondary schooling in America, 1910 to 1940, 1998 January; Goldin, Claudia; Katz, Lawrence F. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 129 - Conceptions and explanations of trust, 1998 April; Hardin, Russell (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 130 - Distrust, 1998 April; Hardin, Russell (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 131 - The role of market size in the formation of jurisdiction, 1998 January; Casella, Alessandra (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 132 - Anonymous market and group ties in international trade, 1998 June; Casella, Alessandra; Rauch, James E. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 133 - The politics of identity reconsidered: presumptive identification and the limits of strategic essentialism, 1998 June; Hattam, Victoria (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 134 - Overcoming informational barriers to international resource allocation: prices and group ties, 1998 June; Rauch, James E.; Casella, Alessandra (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 135 - Share-holders in relief: the political culture of relief and public jobs in the depression, 1998 June; Gordon, Linda (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 136 - Economics and identity, 1998 August; Kranton, Rachel E; Akerlof, George A (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 137 - "I'm floating in the air:" creation of a Korean transnational space among Korean-Latino-American re-migrants, 1998 August; Park, Kyeyoung (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 138 - Do differences in rates of skill depreciation across scientific fields impact labor market outcomes?, 1998 August; Preston, Anne E. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 139 - A theory of buyer-seller networks, 1998 August; Kranton, Rachel E; Minehart, Deborah F. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 140 - When good defenses make good neighbors: a transaction cost approach to trust and distrust, 1999 January; Levi, Margaret (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 141 - The universal welfare state as a social dilemma, 1999 March; Rothstein, Bo (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 142 - Trust, social dilemmas, and the strategic construction of collective memories, 1999 March; Rothstein, Bo (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 143 - The role of formal theory in comparative research, 1999 March; Swistak, Piotr; Kaminski, Marek M.; Lissowski, Grzegorz (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Government; Policy; World politics
  - 144 - The future of the universal welfare state: an institutional approach, 1999 March; Rothstein, Bo (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 145 - The evolution of norms, 1999 June; Swistak, Piotr; Bendor, Jonathan (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 146 - Structural Shifts and Institutional Capacity: possibilities for ethnic cooperation and conflict in urban settings, 1999 July; Jones-Correa, Michael (1965) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 147 - Constructing Race Policy in the United States and Great Britain: history and politics in the development of employment discrimination policy, 1999 July; Lieberman, Robert C. (1964) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 148 - American Riots: structure, institutions, and history, 1999 July; Jones-Correa, Michael (1965) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 149 - Race, State and Inequality in the United States, Great Britain, and France, 1999 June; Lieberman, Robert C. (1964) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 150 - Black-White Earnings Inequality, Employment Rates, and Incarceration, 1999 November; Western, Bruce; Petit, Becky (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 151 - Race, neighborhood poverty and participation in voluntary associations, 1999 November; Stoll, Michael A. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - 152 - Social capital, neighborhood poverty, and joblessness, 1962-1965; Stoll, Michael A.; Melendez, Edwin (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - 153 - The meaning and measurement of social competence from a developmental perspective, 2000 January; Schultz, Lynn Hickey; Selman, Robert L. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - 154 - An experimental study of belief Learning Using Elicited Beliefs, 2000 January; Schotter, Andrew; Nyarko, Yaw (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - 155 - Social Learning and Coordination Conventions in Inter-generational Games: An Experiment in Lamarckian Evolutionary Dynamics, 2000 January; Schotter, Andrew; Sopher, Barry (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 156 - Understanding young women's marriage decisions: the role of labor and marriage market conditions, 2000 January; Blau, Francine D.; Kahn, Lawrence M.; Waldfogel, Jane (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 157 - Wage Inequality, Collective Bargaining, and Relative Employment 1985-1994: evidence from 15 OECD countries, 2000 January; Kahn, Lawrence M. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 158 - Creating Culture in the Lab: Equilibrium Conventions in Inter-generational Ultimatum Games, 2000 May; Schotter, Andrew; Sopher, Barry (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 159 - Learning by Not Doing: an Experimental Investigation of Observational Learning, 2000 May; Schotter, Andrew; Merlo, Antonio (Box 7, Folder 32)